Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and if you've been following along with us recently, you'll know that we
我是Catherine，如果你最近一直跟着我们学习，你会知道我们
have a series about interviewing in English.
有一个关于英语面试的系列节目。
And so today we have the very last episode of that series.
所以今天是我们这个系列的最后一集。
That's right.
没错。
Today is the last part of our interview series and we're basically just saying goodbye and
今天是我们面试系列的最后一部分，我们基本上是在说再见，
we're doing some other things when you're leaving an interview.
同时也会讲到离开面试时要做的一些其他事情。
It's very important the things that you say.
你说的话非常重要。
That's right because this is the last thing that you're going to do in the interview so
没错，因为这是你在面试中做的最后一件事，
it's what your interviewer will remember.
所以面试官会记住它。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
那么让我们听听今天的对话，我们一会儿回来。
Well Rebecca, is there anything else you need to know for now?
嗯，Rebecca，你现在还有什么需要了解的吗？
I don't think so Mr. Parsons.
我想没有了，Parsons先生。
I think you have covered all the main points for me.
我觉得你已经为我涵盖了所有要点。
Okay, well listen.
好的，听着。
Here's my business card with my mobile number.
这是我的名片，上面有我的手机号码。
If any other questions spring to mind, don't hesitate to contact me.
如果还有其他问题，请随时联系我。
Of course you can also call Ms. Childs too.
当然，你也可以给Childs女士打电话。
Great.
太好了。
When can I expect to hear from you?
我什么时候能收到您的回复？
Well we are finishing the short list interviews tomorrow so we will certainly have a decision
嗯，我们明天会完成入围名单的面试，所以肯定会在
made by early next week.
下周初做出决定。
Ms. Childs will call you to discuss more on Monday or Tuesday.
Childs女士会在周一或周二给你打电话讨论更多细节。
How does that sound?
你觉得怎么样？
That sounds perfect.
听起来很完美。
Thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me Mr. Parsons.
非常感谢您抽出时间和我谈话，Parsons先生。
The pleasure is all mine Rebecca.
这是我的荣幸，Rebecca。
I hope to hear from you very soon.
希望很快能收到您的消息。
Absolutely.
当然。
Thanks for coming Rebecca.
谢谢你来，Rebecca。
Goodbye.
再见。
Alright, great.
好的，太棒了。
So really good things from Rebecca.
所以Rebecca做得很好。
She said some very interesting things, key things there.
她说了一些非常有趣的话，关键点在那里。
So why don't we take a look at those on Language Takeaway.
那么让我们在“语言要点”部分看看这些内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
At the beginning of the end of the interview, Rebecca says, listen, I think you have covered
在面试结束的开始，Rebecca说，听着，我觉得你已经为我
all the main points for me.
涵盖了所有要点。
So this is after Mr. Parsons asks her if she has questions.
这是在Parsons先生问她是否有问题之后。
And this word covered is very important.
而“covered”这个词非常重要。
That's right.
没错。
So if we talk about cover, to cover the main points or to cover a topic, it means to discuss
所以如果我们说“cover”，覆盖要点或覆盖一个话题，意思是彻底讨论
it thoroughly or to have it finished.
或完成它。
Right.
对。
So if I still have questions, we have not covered everything.
所以如果我还有问题，我们就没有覆盖所有内容。
But if I did ask all the questions that I have, then we've covered everything.
但如果我问了所有问题，那我们就覆盖了一切。
So the verb here is to cover.
所以这里的动词是“to cover”。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So Rebecca says, well, you know what, here's my business card with my mobile number.
所以Rebecca说，嗯，你知道吗，这是我的名片，上面有我的手机号码。
So this word business card, key element of any interview or any business situation.
所以“business card”这个词，是任何面试或任何商务场合的关键元素。
As you say, a key part of any business interaction.
正如你所说，是任何商务互动的关键部分。
So a business card is a very small card, usually thick, and it has a person's name, job, phone
所以名片是一张很小的卡片，通常很厚，上面有人的名字、职位、电话
number and sometimes email address now on the card.
号码，现在有时还有电子邮件地址。
So the information can change, but it's a contact card basically for one person.
所以信息可以变化，但它基本上是一个人的联系卡。
That's right.
没错。
So it's important to have around, especially in situations like this.
所以随身携带很重要，尤其是在这种情况下。
Okay.
好的。
And moving on, he also told her that if she has any other questions to not hesitate and
继续往下，他还告诉她，如果她还有其他问题，不要犹豫，
to contact him.
联系他。
This is a very common phrase.
这是一个非常常见的短语。
Don't hesitate to contact me or don't hesitate to ask.
“Don't hesitate to contact me”或“don't hesitate to ask”。
That's right.
没错。
So to hesitate means to be nervous about something or to maybe not do it because you're uncomfortable.
所以“hesitate”意思是做某事时紧张，或者因为不舒服而不去做。
So, you know, Marco, I want to ask you something, but I'm not sure if I want to ask you, maybe
所以，你知道，Marco，我想问你点事，但我不确定是否要问你，也许
you'll be angry or so.
你会生气之类的。
I'm hesitating.
我在犹豫。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
The verb here is to hesitate.
这里的动词是“to hesitate”。
You have doubts.
你有疑虑。
I have doubts.
我有疑虑。
And so he says, don't hesitate to contact me.
所以他说，不要犹豫，联系我。
That means any questions, any issues, please call me.
这意味着任何问题、任何情况，请给我打电话。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And Mr. Parson said that they are finishing the short list of interviews tomorrow.
而Parsons先生说他们明天会完成入围名单的面试。
So what does it mean a short list?
那么“short list”是什么意思？
Well, a short list is something we talk about during the interview process because the interviewer,
嗯，“short list”是我们在面试过程中谈到的东西，因为面试官，
so in this case, Mr. Parsons will have a long list of people who want the job.
在这种情况下，Parsons先生会有一长串想要这份工作的人。
And maybe after the first interview, he will cut the list down to a very small number of
也许第一次面试之后，他会把名单缩减到很少的
people, 10 or 15.
人，10到15个。
And that is called the short list.
这就叫做入围名单。
So those are the people who did well on the first interview, but who maybe should come
所以这些人是第一次面试表现不错，但可能还需要
back for a second or third interview.
回来参加第二次或第三次面试。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
A lot of great things there.
有很多精彩的内容。
Why don't we take a break?
我们休息一下怎么样？
Let's go back and listen to the dialogue.
让我们回去听听对话。
Let's see what Mr. Parsons and Rebecca said.
看看帕森斯先生和丽贝卡说了什么。
And we'll be back with some really good phrases that you can close off an interview with.
我们稍后会回来，介绍一些可以用来结束面试的好短语。
Well, Rebecca, is there anything else you need to know for now?
嗯，丽贝卡，你现在还有什么需要了解的吗？
I don't think so, Mr. Parsons.
我想没有了，帕森斯先生。
I think you have covered all the main points for me.
我觉得你已经把主要要点都给我讲清楚了。
Okay, well, listen.
好的，嗯，听着。
Here's my business card with my mobile number.
这是我的名片，上面有我的手机号码。
If any other questions spring to mind, don't hesitate to contact me.
如果还有其他问题突然想到，请随时联系我。
Of course, you can also call Ms. Childs, too.
当然，你也可以给柴尔兹女士打电话。
Great.
太好了。
When can I expect to hear from you?
我什么时候能收到您的消息？
Well, we are finishing the short list interviews tomorrow, so we will certainly have a decision
嗯，我们明天结束入围名单的面试，所以肯定会在
made by early next week.
下周初做出决定。
Ms. Childs will call you to discuss more on Monday or Tuesday.
柴尔兹女士会在周一或周二给你打电话，进一步讨论。
How does that sound?
你觉得怎么样？
That sounds perfect.
听起来很完美。
Thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me, Mr. Parsons.
非常感谢您抽出时间和我谈话，帕森斯先生。
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
这是我的荣幸，丽贝卡。
I hope to hear from you very soon.
我希望能很快收到您的消息。
Absolutely.
当然。
Thanks for coming, Rebecca.
谢谢你来，丽贝卡。
Goodbye.
再见。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at those phrases we mentioned on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看在“流利度构建器”中提到的那些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So let's go back to the beginning where Mr. Parsons is talking about questions that Rebecca
让我们回到开头，帕森斯先生谈到丽贝卡可能
might have.
有的问题。
And so Mr. Parsons says, if any other questions spring to mind, don't hesitate to contact
帕森斯先生说，如果还有其他问题突然想到，请随时联系
me.
我。
So this phrase, spring to mind, is very interesting.
所以这个短语“spring to mind”非常有趣。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Well, basically if something springs to your mind or springs to mind, it means that it
嗯，基本上，如果某件事突然出现在你的脑海里或突然想到，意思是它
comes very suddenly and quickly into your mind.
非常突然和快速地进入你的脑海。
It just pops into your head.
它只是突然出现在你的脑子里。
Wow.
哇。
So to spring or springs in this case is like jumping.
所以这里的“spring”或“springs”就像跳跃一样。
So something hits your mind very quickly, comes into your mind very quickly.
所以某件事很快地击中你的脑海，很快地进入你的脑海。
So oh, I don't really have any ideas, Marco, for that party next week, but if anything
所以，哦，马可，我对下周的派对真的没什么想法，但如果有什么
springs to mind, you should let me know.
突然想到，你应该告诉我。
Okay.
好的。
If you have any sudden ideas or anything you suddenly remember, that's what it means to
如果你突然有想法或突然想起什么，这就是“spring to mind”的意思。
spring to mind.
突然想到。
Okay.
好的。
So taking a look at these expressions that Rebecca used when she's leaving, for example,
那么看看丽贝卡离开时使用的这些表达，例如，
you know that you finished the interview and a typical question that you want to make is,
你知道面试结束了，一个典型的问题你想问的是，
when can I expect to hear from you?
“我什么时候能收到您的消息？”
This is a great question at the end of an interview because it's basically a way of
这是面试结束时的一个好问题，因为它基本上是一种
saying, listen, I'm interested in this job.
说“听着，我对这份工作感兴趣”的方式。
When will you call me about it?
你什么时候会给我打电话谈这件事？
And so the phrase, when can I expect to hear from you means, when will you tell me your
所以短语“when can I expect to hear from you”的意思是，你什么时候告诉我你的
decision?
决定？
That's right.
没错。
But it's a lot more polite and formal and better than saying, when are you going to
但这比说“你什么时候给我打电话”要礼貌、正式得多，也更好。
call me?
给我打电话？
Yeah, you would never say that in an interview because it makes you sound desperate, like
是的，你在面试中绝不会那么说，因为那会让你听起来很绝望，好像
you really need the job.
你真的需要这份工作。
In this case, you know, when can I expect to hear from you?
在这种情况下，你知道，“我什么时候能收到您的消息？”
It's like, oh, well, you know, I hope that you'll get in touch with me.
就像，哦，嗯，你知道，我希望你能联系我。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So she explained that they're shortlisting everything and that they will be in touch
所以她解释说他们正在筛选入围名单，并且他们会很快
with her very soon.
联系她。
And she said, wow, that sounds perfect.
她说，哇，听起来很完美。
Thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me.
非常感谢您抽出时间和我谈话。
Okay, so this phrase, thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me, it's very
好的，所以这个短语“thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me”非常
long.
长。
But you know what thank you very much means.
但你知道“thank you very much”是什么意思。
The key here is for taking the time to do something.
这里的关键是“for taking the time to do something”。
Now what does this mean?
这是什么意思？
What's another way we can use this?
我们还能怎么用这个？
It's basically saying thank you so much for giving me an opportunity to talk to you.
这基本上是在说，非常感谢你给我机会和你交谈。
I know you're very busy and I know you don't have a lot of time.
我知道你很忙，也知道你时间不多。
So thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me.
所以非常感谢你抽出时间和我说话。
Right.
对。
So you could even use this with a teacher at school.
所以你甚至可以在学校对老师用这句话。
You know, you have a question, your teacher is busy, but your teacher makes some time
你知道，你有个问题，你的老师很忙，但老师还是抽出时间
to meet with you.
来见你。
You say, hey, listen, professor or listen, teacher, thank you so much for taking the
你说，嘿，听着，教授或老师，非常感谢你抽出
time to speak to me.
时间和我说话。
You're just demonstrating that you appreciate the effort and the time.
你只是在表明你感激这份努力和时间。
And you're being very polite.
而且你表现得很有礼貌。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And then the last phrase, when Rebecca is leaving the room, they're shaking hands maybe
然后最后一句话，当Rebecca离开房间时，他们可能在握手，
and Rebecca says, I hope to hear from you very soon.
然后Rebecca说，我希望很快能收到你的消息。
You can say I hope to hear from you soon.
你可以说，我希望很快能收到你的消息。
But in this case, she's saying, listen, I really want this job.
但在这个情况下，她在说，听着，我真的很想要这份工作。
She doesn't want to say, call me, you know, call me tomorrow.
她不想说，给我打电话，你知道，明天给我打电话。
She says, I hope to hear from you soon.
她说，我希望很快能收到你的消息。
I hope that this works out that I get the job.
我希望这件事能成，我能得到这份工作。
Right.
对。
So she's basically demonstrating a lot of interest saying, well, I really like the job
所以她基本上表现出很大的兴趣，说，嗯，我真的很喜欢这份工作，
and I really would like for you to call me and give me good news.
而且我真的希望你能打电话给我，给我好消息。
So I hope to hear from you soon.
所以我希望很快能收到你的消息。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So let's listen to today's dialogue one more time and we'll be back in a moment to talk
那么让我们再听一遍今天的对话，我们稍后会回来
a little bit more about how to end an interview.
再聊一聊如何结束面试。
Well Rebecca, is there anything else you need to know for now?
嗯，Rebecca，你现在还有什么需要了解的吗？
I don't think so, Mr. Parsons.
我想没有了，Parsons先生。
I think you have covered all the main points for me.
我想你已经为我涵盖了所有要点。
Okay.
好的。
Well, listen, here's my business card with my mobile number.
嗯，听着，这是我的名片，上面有我的手机号码。
If any other questions spring to mind, don't hesitate to contact me.
如果还有其他问题想到，请随时联系我。
Of course, you can also call Ms. Childs too.
当然，你也可以给Childs女士打电话。
Great.
太好了。
Um, when can I expect to hear from you?
嗯，我什么时候能收到你的消息？
Well, we are finishing the short list interviews tomorrow, so we will certainly have a decision
嗯，我们明天会完成最后一轮面试，所以肯定会在
made by early next week.
下周初做出决定。
Ms. Childs will call you to discuss more on Monday or Tuesday.
Childs女士会在周一或周二打电话给你，进一步讨论。
How does that sound?
你觉得怎么样？
That sounds perfect.
听起来很完美。
Thank you very much for taking the time to speak to me, Mr. Parsons.
非常感谢你抽出时间和我说话，Parsons先生。
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
这是我的荣幸，Rebecca。
I hope to hear from you very soon.
我希望很快能收到你的消息。
Absolutely.
当然。
Thanks for coming, Rebecca.
谢谢你来，Rebecca。
Goodbye.
再见。
So this is a great way of ending an interview.
所以这是一个很好的结束面试的方式。
Rebecca did a really good job, and I think there are a couple of suggestions or tips
Rebecca做得很好，我想你有一些建议或小贴士
that you would like to give our users.
想给我们的用户。
Yeah, well, one of them is don't, at the end of the interview, ask the person if you have
是的，嗯，其中一个建议是，在面试结束时，不要问对方你是否
the job.
得到了这份工作。
They'll say, we will be in touch, or thank you so much for coming in.
他们会说，我们会联系你，或者非常感谢你来。
But if they don't say, we would really like to have you join this company, then you probably
但如果他们没说，我们真的很希望你能加入这家公司，那你可能
shouldn't ask.
就不该问。
You should say, you know, when can I expect to hear from you?
你应该说，你知道，我什么时候能收到你的消息？
That's more polite.
这样更礼貌。
Because I think a lot of times, if you didn't get the job, it makes the interviewer feel
因为我觉得很多时候，如果你没得到工作，会让面试官感到
very uncomfortable.
非常不舒服。
But also, it's just a polite thing to do.
而且，这也是礼貌的做法。
So be careful with that.
所以要注意这一点。
And I've also been told from people in business that if you do receive a job offer, don't
而且我还从商界人士那里听说，如果你确实收到了工作邀请，不要
accept right away.
立刻接受。
Say I will think about it, and I'll get back in touch with you.
说我会考虑一下，然后我会再联系你。
Oh, OK.
哦，好的。
Kind of like a strategy maybe to better negotiate the terms and conditions.
有点像一种策略，也许是为了更好地谈判条款和条件。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So you want to take that information, you want to go home, you want to think about it,
所以你想带着这些信息，回家，好好想想，
talk about it with your wife or your husband, and decide, is this something I want?
和你的妻子或丈夫讨论一下，然后决定，这是不是我想要的？
And then you can contact the employer.
然后你可以联系雇主。
Right.
对。
Yeah, I think that's a very good idea.
是的，我觉得这是个非常好的主意。
And also, I think it's not a wise thing to call or contact the employer asking if you've
而且，我觉得打电话或联系雇主问你是否得到了工作，
got the job or asking if they have any news yet, because I think that can be a little
或者问他们有没有消息，是不明智的，因为我觉得那可能会有点
bit annoying.
烦人。
But if they say, we will be in touch on Tuesday, and it's a week later, and they never got
但如果他们说，我们会在周二联系你，但一周后他们还没
back to you, send a follow up.
回复你，那就发个跟进。
Of course.
当然。
A follow up is an email or a letter or even a phone call where you say, listen, I'm really
跟进就是发一封邮件、一封信，甚至打个电话，说，听着，我真的很
glad I got to meet you today.
高兴今天能见到你。
I hope that we have the opportunity to work together in the future.
我希望我们将来有机会一起合作。
Always be in touch.
保持联系。
Sincerely, and then your name.
此致敬礼，然后写上你的名字。
Kind of like a reminder.
有点像提醒。
It's a reminder, like, I want the job.
这是一种提醒，比如，我想要这份工作。
Here's my information.
这是我的信息。
Let's do this.
我们开始吧。
Or at least if I didn't get the job, let me know that I didn't get it.
或者至少如果我没得到这份工作，让我知道我没被录用。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
All right.
好的。
So a lot of great advice here.
这里有很多很棒的建议。
Great things coming.
好事即将来临。
And we'll be back again with another series.
我们会再回来推出另一个系列。
We're going to have a presentation series.
我们将推出一个演示系列。
So be sure to keep an eye out for that.
所以请务必留意。
And if you have any other questions or comments, we're always at EnglishPod.com where you can
如果你还有其他问题或评论，我们一直在EnglishPod.com上，你可以
find us.
找到我们。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
Bye-bye.
再见。